

# COLM ROGERS



#### Address

Groβe Tulln Straβe 22, 3041 Siegersdorf



## & Phone

(0043) 660 9591035



colmrogers91@gmail.com

#### SOCIAL



#### LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/colmrogers/



#### Website

https://rogers-

1991.github.io/Portfolio Website/

#### EDUCATION

# **Higher Diploma in Science with Computing**

Griffith College Dublin 1<sup>st</sup> Class Honours / 2020 - 2021

Certificate, Diploma, 2 Higher Diplomas and 2 Mixing and **Mastering Awards in** Sound Technology in Music/Film

Academy of Sound Dublin Distinctions / 2016-2018

## **BA Connect in Film Studies** with English and Philosophy

**NUI** Galway 2<sup>nd</sup> Class Honours / 2010 - 2015

#### **BA in Film Studies**

UC Berkeley 3.67/4 GPA / 2014 - 2014

#### PROFILE

Hardworking & achievement-oriented student recently graduated with a 1st Class Honours Higher Diploma in Science in Computing. Honours graduate of Film Studies with Arts from NUI Galway. Strong technical aptitude, with a 2:1 Honours standard in English and writing, organisation and communication skills and a sincere passion for learning more.

Direct project management experience, handling entire post-production process of film projects, through my post-production company, Rogers Sound. Proficient in the use of audio and video software with experience in various departments, both on location and post-production.

## WORK HISTORY

#### Sound Supervisor, Designer and Editor / Video Editor

Freelance - Dublin

10.2016 - 04.2020

- Supervised entire post-production process of a feature film, including audio, visual, VFX and colour.
- Arranged production meetings and supervised projects sent to different production houses.
- Worked in all audio post-production departments, provided video edit, and supervised Colour, VFX and Music.
- Recorded and mixed sound on-location.
- Created and managed a data library of audio/video files for feature projects.
- Transcoded raw video footage to low-resolution proxies for editing.

## **Contact Administrator and Customer Care Representative**

J1 Ireland – Roscommon

01.2018 - 05.2018 / 01.2019 - 05.2019

- Designed and implemented an application monitoring system, which enabled the business to meet its target of completing over 300 outstanding applications, while simultaneously managing new applications helping to reach all project goals on time.
- Secured over 30 US jobs by meeting and negotiating with owner of Bubba Gump Shrimp in Chicago.
- Contacted US Visa Sponsors and applicants daily regarding completed application forms.

#### SOFTWARE

- Java and JavaFX
- MySQL
- HTML and CSS
- TailWind
- JavaScript and Node.js
- Bootstrap
- React
- PHP
- Avid Pro Tools 10, 11, 12
- Adobe Premiere Pro
- Davinci Resolve 14, 15

#### INTERESTS





Cooking

**Playing Music** 





Gaming

Movies

## LANGUAGES

#### **English**

Native Speaker

#### German

Beginner (learning)

## WORK HISTORY (continued)

#### **Work Experience**

Beacon Studios - Dublin

06.2017 - 08.2017

- Provided a Sound Effects mix and final mix on #Navan2030 promo ad for Irish national TV personality, Hector Ó hEochagáin.
- Answered the phone at reception, took down bookings and inquiries.
- Shadowed sessions with clients.

#### ACHIEVEMENTS

- Owner and Founder of freelance Audio Post-Production Company, Rogers
  Sound
- Voted Class Rep in Computer Science Course in Griffith College
- Designed portfolio website: https://rogers-1991.github.io/Portfolio\_Website
- Designed website: www.rogerssound.com with Adobe XD (Currently offline)
- Produced, wrote, and directed short film, Chemical Lover
- Built own custom PC
- Voted Equipment Manager of NUIG's Rock (Music) Society
- Credited on 2 Feature Films
- Only student from John Huston Film School to be accepted into UC Berkeley
- Gave film audio lectures at Filmbase, Dublin

# QUALITIES

- Technical Competency
- Strong Work Ethic
- Strong Problem Solver
- Creativity
- Patience
- Persistence
- Communication
- Flexibility

## REFEREES

## **Matt Rogers**

Director/Owner of J1 Ireland

Phone (00353) 86 8488792 Email matt@j1ireland.com

#### **Noel Storey**

Owner of Beacon Studios

Phone (00353) 167 62474 Email noel@beaconstudios.net